<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
  ! This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
  ! Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
  ! disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
  ! accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
  ! into with Oracle.
  !
  ! ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
  ! SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
  ! IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
  ! PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
  ! SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
  ! THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
  !
  ! Copyright (c) 2015. All Rights reserved
  !
-->
<book xml:id  ="oam-deployment-utility"
      xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
      xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
      version ="5.0"
      lang    ="de">
  <info>
    <title>Access Manager Deployment</title>
    <subtitle>Technical Reference Guide</subtitle>
    <edition>October, 2019</edition>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
        <personname>
          <firstname>Sophie</firstname>
          <surname>Strecke</surname>
        </personname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <personname>
          <firstname>Dieter</firstname>
          <surname>Steding</surname>
        </personname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <publishername>Oracle Consulting Services</publishername>
    <copyright>
      <year>2011</year>
      <year>2012</year>
      <year>2013</year>
      <year>2014</year>
      <year>2015</year>
      <year>2016</year>
      <year>2017</year>
      <year>2018</year>
      <year>2019</year>
      <holder role="https://www.oracle.com/de/consulting/">Oracle Consulting Services</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice>
      <para>All rights reserved. No part of this guide may be reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any means,
            electronic or mechanical, including photocopying, recording, or by any information storage and retrieval
            system, without written permission from the publisher, except for the inclusion of brief quotations in a
            review.</para>
    </legalnotice>
    <legalnotice>
      <title>Warning and Disclaimer</title>
      <para>Every effort has been made to make this book as complete and accurate as possible, but Oracle Consulting
            Services makes no warranties, either express or implied, regarding the content or its fitness for any
            particular purpose. The information is provided on an as-is basis. The author and Oracle Consulting Services
            shall have neither liability nor responsibility to any person or entity with respect to any loss or damages
            arising from the information contained in this book.</para>
      <para>This guide contains links to third-party Web sites that are not under the control of Oracle Consulting
            Services, and Oracle Consulting Services and the author are not responsible for the content of any linked
            site. If you access a third-party website mentioned in this guide, then you do so at your own risk. Oracle
            Consulting Services provides these links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of the link does not imply
            that Oracle Consulting Services or the author endorses or accepts any responsibility for the content of
            those third-party sites.</para>
    </legalnotice>
    <legalnotice>
      <title>Trademarks</title>
      <para>All terms mentioned in this book that are known to be trademarks or service marks have been appropriately
            capitalized. Use of a term in this book should not be regarded as affecting the validity of any trademark or
            service mark.</para>
    </legalnotice>
  </info>
  <!--
  <xi:include href="chapter/01-preface.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="chapter/02-whats-new.xml"/>
  -->
</book>