<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
 |  Oracle Deutschland BV & Co. KG
 |
 |  This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
 |  Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
 |  disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
 |  accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
 |  into with Oracle.
 |
 |  ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
 |  SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
 |  IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
 |  PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
 |  SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
 |  THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
 |
 |  Copyright &#xA9; 2022. All Rights reserved
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="igs-backend-about"
         xml:lang="en"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Guide to IAM</title>
  <para>
    Identity and Access Management (IAM) is a framework of business processes, policies and technologies that facilitates the management of electronic or digital identities.
    With an IAM framework in place, information technology (IT) managers can control user access to critical information within their organizations.
    Systems used for IAM include single sign-on systems,
    <link xl:show="new"
          xl:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help:Two-factor_authentication"
          xl:role="http://docbook.org/xlink/role/olink">
      <citetitle>two-factor authentication</citetitle>
    </link>,
    <link xl:show="new"
          xl:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication"
          xl:role="http://docbook.org/xlink/role/olink">
      <citetitle>multifactor authentication</citetitle>
    </link> and
    <link xl:show="new"
          xl:href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Identity_management"
          xl:role="http://docbook.org/xlink/role/olink">
      <citetitle>privileged account management</citetitle>
    </link>.
    These technologies also provide the ability to securely store identity and profile data as well as data governance functions to ensure that only data that is necessary and relevant is shared.
  </para>
  <para>
    IAM systems can be deployed on premises, provided by a third-party vendor through a cloud-based subscription model or deployed in a hybrid model. 
  </para>
  <para>
    On a fundamental level, IAM encompasses the following components:
    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
      <listitem>
        how individuals are identified in a system (understand the difference between identity management and authentication)
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        how roles are identified in a system and how they are assigned to individuals
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        adding, removing and updating individuals and their roles in a system
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        assigning levels of access to individuals or groups of individuals
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        protecting the sensitive data within the system and securing the system itself
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  <section xml:id="igs-backend-about-importance">
    <title>Why is IAM important?</title>
    <para>
      Businesses leaders and IT departments are under increased regulatory and organizational pressure to protect access to corporate resources.
      As a result, they can no longer rely on manual and error-prone processes to assign and track user privileges.
      IAM automates these tasks and enables granular access control and auditing of all corporate assets on premises and in the cloud.
    </para>
    <para>
      IAM, which has an ever-increasing list of features -- including biometrics, behavior analytics and AI -- is well suited to the rigors of the new security landscape.
      For example, IAM's tight control of resource access in highly distributed and dynamic environments aligns with the industry's transition from firewalls to zero-trust models and with the security requirements of IoT.
    </para>
    <para>
      While IT professionals might think IAM is for larger organizations with bigger budgets, in reality, the technology is accessible for companies of all sizes.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>