<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
 |  Oracle Deutschland BV & Co. KG
 |
 |  This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
 |  Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
 |  disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
 |  accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
 |  into with Oracle.
 |
 |  ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
 |  SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
 |  IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
 |  PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
 |  SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
 |  THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
 |
 |  Copyright &#xA9; 2022. All Rights reserved
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="igs-backend-install"
         xml:lang="en"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Install the Database Schema</title>
  <para>
    This chapter describes how to install the <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis> Data Model database objects.
  </para>
  <para>
    This guide will not detail how to set up an instance of the target database.
    Consult the documentation of your target database on how to do that.
    <important>
      <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis> supports at the time being Oracle&#xAE; as a target database only.
    </important>
  </para>
  <para>
    To install the database schema required for <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis>, a set of scripts provided with prepared DDL statements.
    Those scripts create all required tables and default indices.
  </para>
  <para>
    To be able to install any objects you need access to the Oracle Database either locally or remotely.
    An installation of <emphasis>SQL*Plus</emphasis> is required to be able to execute the provided scripts.
  </para>
  <warning>
    The database role <emphasis role="strong">DBA</emphasis> is required to perform the installation.
  </warning>
  <para>
    The installation of the base objects, which are generally required for each additional service within the <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis>, consists of:
    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
      <listitem>
        <link linkend='igs-backend-install-sys'>Create System Objects</link>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <link linkend='igs-backend-install-all'>Create Schema Objects</link>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>c  <section xml:id="igs-backend-install-sys">
    <title>Create System Objects</title>
    <para>
      Creating the system objects leads to the creation of a tablespace and the owner of the schema with the necessary rights in the database.
    </para>
    To install the system objects execute the steps:
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open a command line for the operating system from which access to the database instance is possible.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Locate the directory of the provided scripts and navigate to it:
        </para>
        <programlisting>cd <emphasis>&#x3C;IGS_BASE&#x3E;</emphasis>/governanceBackend/src/main/resources/igs</programlisting>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Create the storage (tablespace) and the database schema owner <emphasis>igd_igs</emphasis> of <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis> by executing the following command:
        </para>
        <programlisting>sqlplus / as sysdba @sys</programlisting>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
       After running the script to create the system objects, the log files should be checked for any errors that may have occurred during execution.
       These log files are in the same directory as the script used to load the database schema (see step 3).
    </para>
    <note>
      When running the script for the first time, it is normal to encounter errors like <emphasis>ORA-01918</emphasis>.
    </note>c  </section>
  <section xml:id="igs-backend-install-all">
    <title>Create Schema Objects</title>
    <para>
      To install the schema objects execute the steps:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Open a command line for the operating system from which access to the database instance is possible.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Locate the directory of the provided scripts and navigate to it:
        </para>
        <programlisting>cd <emphasis>&#x3C;IGS_BASE&#x3E;</emphasis>/governanceBackend/src/main/resources/igs</programlisting>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Load the database schema of <emphasis>Identity Governance Services</emphasis> by executing the following command:
        </para>
        <programlisting>sqlplus / as sysdba @create</programlisting>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
       After running the script to create the schema objects, the log files should be checked for any errors that may have occurred during execution.
       These log files are in the same directory as the script used to load the database schema (see step 3).
    </para>
    <note>
      When running the script for the first time, it is normal to encounter errors like <emphasis>ORA-04080</emphasis> or <emphasis>ORA-00942</emphasis>.
    </note>
  </section>
</chapter>