<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
  ! This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
  ! Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
  ! disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
  ! accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
  ! into with Oracle.
  !
  ! ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
  ! SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
  ! IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
  ! PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
  ! SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
  ! THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
  !
  ! Copyright (c) 2015. All Rights reserved
  !
-->
<chapter xml:id     ="oim-general"
         xmlns      ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         version    ="5.0">
  <title>Importing and Exporting Deployments</title>
  <para>The Deployment Manager is a tool for exporting and importing Identity Manager Configurations. The Deployment
        Manager lets you export the objects that constitute the Identity Manager configuration. Usually, you use the
        Deployment Manager to migrate a configuration from one deployment to another, for example, from a test to a
        production deployment, or to create a backup of your system.</para>
  <para>You can export objects from your Identity Manager system and save them in an XML file. This generated files you
        can later use to import to another deployment.</para>
  <para>The following are limitations of the Deployment Manager:</para>
  <section>
    <title>Audience</title>
    <para>This guide is intended for resource administrators and target system integration teams.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Exporting Deployments</title>
    <para>The Deployment Manager Export handles the following categories of information:</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Importing Deployments</title>
    <para>Objects that were exported to an XML file by using the Deployment Manager can be imported into Oracle Identity
          Manager by using the Deployment Manager. You can import all or part of the XML file, and you can import
          multiple XML files at once. The Deployment Manager ensures that the dependencies for any objects you are
          importing are available, either in the import or in your system.</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
