<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
Provide your change documentation here for each change you made to
implementation, configuration, documentation and all other resources
managed by the versioning tool. Each change gets a seperate tag within
this file, the newest change at the top.
Duplicate an existing entry and adapt the values.
DO NOT DELETE ANY ENTRY!
-->
<changes updated="$Author$">
  <release id="12.1.3.0">
    <build id="00.07" date="21/12/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Improved Reconciliation Event handling</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.06" date="20/12/2018">
      <function id="Identity Foundation Library">Set database filter parameter in a type safe manner due to the enforced type constraints of Oracle JDBC driver</function>
      <function id="Framework">Upgraded to BP 181016</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.05" date="17/12/2018">
      <function id="Request PrePopulate Adapter">Moved Reource Bundle to Plugin</function>
      <function id="Plugin">Renamed deployment descriptor from ocs-eventhandler-dm.xml to ocs-handler-dm.xml</function>
      <function id="Plugin">Renamed deployment archive from ocs-eventhandler.zip to ocs-handler.zip</function>
      <function id="AbstractStringAdapter">Handling of java.sql.ResultSet changed in method profileEncrypted</function>
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.04" date="20/12/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.03" date="20/12/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.02" date="13/12/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.01" date="27/07/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.00" date="07/06/2018">
      <function id="Framework">Maintenance porting to 12c</function>
    </build>
  </release>
  <release id="3.1.0.0">
    <build id="00.39" date="14/07/2017">
      <function id="Identity Foundation Library">Splitted naming inteface Lookup in the definition part and the value part. The new inteface which belongs to the value part is LookupValue</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.38" date="28/06/2017">
      <defect id="DE-000222">Priority attribute isn't declared in interface oracle.iam.identity.foundation.naming.AccessPolicy</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000221">Class DatabaseConnection has unnecessary dependencies on package com.oracle.oim.gcp</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.37" date="03/05/2017">
      <function id="Identity Foundation Library">Extended Access Policy Naming Interface with definitions belonging to Policy Owner</function>
      <function id="Identity Foundation Library">Fix issue of field code misspelled in interface oracle.iam.identity.foundation.naming.ResourceObject.java to resolve the resource object type.</function>
      <function id="Identity Foundation Library">Fix issue in oracle.iam.identity.foundation.persistent.DatabaseStatement.java to handle multiple entities which are part of the same query.</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.36" date="31/03/2017">
      <function id="Identity Manager">Fixed some typos in terms of formatting, comments and javadoc.</function>
      <function id="Utility Foundation Library">troduced date transformers for external format yyyy-mm-dd hh:mi:ss</function>
      <function id="Offline Target Service">Fixed parsing of xml offline account reconciliation to parse entitlement attributes</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.35" date="31/03/2017">
      <function id="Deployment Utility Library">Sandbox generation continued</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.34" date="12/03/2016">
      <function id="Flat File Connector">Improved functionality to manager files which isn't anything else as text only</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.26" date="05/21/2016">
      <function id="Web Service Connector">One Way operations implemented to complete functionality</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.25" date="05/15/2016">
      <function id="Web Service Connector">Final declaration on WebServiceConnector methods which returns URL's removed to allow overriding in subclasses</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.24" date="03/04/2016">
      <function id="Modify Business Roles">Switch back to behavior that its not permitted to change an existing business role</function>

      <defect id="DE-000159">Catalog Item cannot be managed by Access Request Catalog Import if it was soft-deleted.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.17" date="09/20/2015">
      <function id="CSV Flatfile">Timestamp on error files are in the format "yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH-mm-ss.SSSZ".</function>
      <function id="LDIF File">Timestamp on error files are in the format "yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH-mm-ss.SSSZ".</function>
      <function id="Offline Target System">Timestamp on error files are in the format "yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH-mm-ss.SSSZ".</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.13" date="2015/07/06">
      <defect id="DE-000154">Risk Attribute isn't parsed from a BusinessRole Definition.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000153">Attribute Mapping transfer for Trusted Offline Reconciliation maps the logical mapping key instead of the raw data key.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000152">Validating content of a batch during Offline Account Reconciliation reports duplicate accounts.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000151">Initializing of Offline Account Reconciliation fails.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.03" date="07/06/2014">
      <defect id="DE-000131">Lookup Reconciliation throws Exception with uninterpretable message.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.02" date="07/06/2014">
      <function id="DE-000092">Since Release 3.0.1.0-00.02 Job exceptions are no longer reported by deployment.</function>

      <defect id="DE-000130">Constant used to demarcate method entry/exit etc. needs to be part of product independent interfaces.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000129">Batch Size can be defined with a negative value.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000128">Batch Size is an optional argument but if its isn't defined the job loops infinite.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000127">Batch Size is an optional argument but if its isn't defined the job loops infinite.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000126">Batch Size is an optional argument but if its isn't defined the job loops infinite.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000125">atch Size is an optional argument but if its isn't defined the job loops infinite.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000124">Batch Size is an optional argument but if its isn't defined the job loops infinite.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000123">Abstract SchedulerTask defines job attribute as Dependent Task.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000122">Generic Directory Reconciliation does not count ignored events correctly.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000121">Generic Directory Reconciliation does not output identifier of ignored event.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000120">Deployment of a sandbox which archive file does not exists throws NPE.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000119">System Roles assigned to an account are not reconciled from Identity Anayltics.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000117">OCS.OIA.PROVISIONING throws java.lang.NullPointerException.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000116">Log shows "User ID" ignored for "[Ljava.lang.String;@74ca4089" instead of value.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000092">Since Release 3.0.1.0-00.02 Job exceptions are no longer reported by deployment.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.01" date="07/06/2014">
    </build>
    <build id="00.00" date="07/06/2014">
    </build>
  </release>
  <release id="3.0.1.0">
  </release>
  <release id="3.0.0.0">
    <build id="00.32" date="17/02/2015">
    </build>
    <build id="00.31" date="07/06/2014">
      <defect id="DE-000072">ApplicationInstance throws NullPointerException if an existing ApplicationInstance is modified.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000073">After Build 00.29 its no longer possible to assign  to a role or revoke from a role.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000074">After Build 00.29 SystemProperty cannot be created or modified anymore.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000075">Publisheing of sandboxes creates wrong Label Prefix for PreMerge and PostMerge.</defect>
      <defect id="DE-000076">Entreprise User are not revoked in target system if resource is revoked.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.29" date="07/06/2014">
      <defect id="DE-000071">Sorting in LDAP searches is not able to specifiy reverseOrder for SortControl.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.29" date="07/06/2014">
      <defect id="DE-000070">Account is not revoked if Application Instance will be removed.</defect>
    </build>
    <build id="00.12" date="07/06/2014">
      <function id="Foundation Library">Lazy initialization of interface ReconOperationsService in class AbstractReconciliationTask was dropped. Initialization of this interface is now done in the constructor hence the method afterExecution becomes obsolete and was also dropped.</function>
      <function id="Foundation Library">DatabaseConnection offers now following new API's. public static final boolean opened(final Connection connection) Return true if the given Connection is non-null and not closed; otherwise it returns false.</function>
      <function id="Utility Foundation">AbstractDateTransformers offers now following new API's.</function>
      <function id="Utility Foundation">The date value transformer are now writing a warning message to the log if they are not able to transform the passed value leveraging the format the transformer use.</function>
      <function id="Adapter Foundation">The Global UID generator implemented by  oracle.iam.identity.event.spi.GlobalUID is no longer using the legacy API.</function>
      <function id="Adapter Foundation">ll access to the system property configuration relies now on oracle.iam.conf.api.SystemConfigurationService.</function>
      <function id="CSV Flatfile">All kind of reconciliations take care about the new behavior of OIM if an Delete Event has to be created.</function>
      <function id="CSV Flatfile">In previous releases it doesn't matter if all required fields are provided at the time the Delete Event is created.</function>
      <function id="CSV Flatfile">Since 11.1.1 all required fields needs a value before the event can be created.</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">HierarchyTrustedReconciliation takes now care about to test if a reconciliation event has to be created be delegating the test to method ignoreEvent. (This is still not working properly like it does for identities and account, seems to be a bug or not implemented for organizations)</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">HierarchyDeleteRecon validates if the process is applicable by checking the system property 'ORG.DisableDeleteActionEnabled'. If the value provided by this property is configured as 'false' all action executed by the job will fail hence the job will be stop with exception if this property is not configured as 'true'</function>
      <function id="Oracle Identity Analytics">The pre-population of the process form is changed.</function>
      <function id="Oracle Identity Analytics">Parent Organizations and Managers are now copied from the appropriate profile attributes of the organization that will be provisioned.</function>
      <function id="Oracle Identity Analytics">This values are passed from the process directly to the implementation and here all necessary action takes place to resolve the values either in OIA or OIM.</function>
      <function id="Deployment Utility">Starting a job by JonHandler in blocking mode now waits until it's detects that the job is running.</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.11" date="07/06/2014">
      <function id="Foundation Library">The class AbstractProcessHandler has two new method. This makes it easier to work with the legacy API's like PreparedStatementUtil or our own legacy classes to provide an instance of tcDataProvider to constructors and methods.</function>
      <function id="Utility Foundation">The transformation classes especially the Date transformation was extended.</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">The configuration of the Directory Feature implementation allows to define if the backing Directory Service supports Referential Integrity This feature will later be used to move all the work to cleanup the entry container if an entry is deleted to the Directory Service.</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.10" date="07/06/2014">
      <function id="Foundation Library">The class AbstractReconciliationTask has a new method reconcileDescriptor. This method returns the path to reconciliation descriptor in Metadata Store.</function>
      <function id="Foundation Library">The configuration of the Directory Feature implementation allows to define if the backing Directory Service supports Referential Integrity.</function>
      <function id="Foundation Library">This feature will later be used to move all the work to cleanup the entry container if an entry is deleted to the Directory Service.</function>
      <function id="Adapter Library">Standard Event Handlers are added to notify Identities about assignment and revocation of roles.</function>
      <function id="Adapter Library">The EventHandler RoleNotification (package oracle.iam.identity.event.role) is invoked if a role is assigned or revoked from a user.</function>
      <function id="Adapter Library">The EventHandler creates a NotificationEvent that force the engine to invoke the  RoleNotificationResolver (package oracle.iam.identity.event.role).</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">The connector provides now the capabilities of trusted delete reconciliation for organizations.</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">The target/trusted delete reconciliation for identities is in the roadmap and will be implemented in the next build.</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">The same will be done for the target delete reconciliation for organizations.</function>
      <function id="Generic Directory Service">The same will be done for the target delete reconciliation for organizations.</function>
      <function id="Deployment Utility">Organization are now part of the deployment utilities.</function>
      <function id="Deployment Utility">Organizations can be created, modified and deleted.</function>
    </build>
    <build id="00.08" date="07/06/2014">
      <defect   id="DE-000070">Members in AbstractServiceTask$Batch has to be of primitive int instead of primitive long.</defect>
    </build>
  </release>
  <release id="1.0.0.0">
  </release>
</changes>