<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
 |  Oracle Deutschland GmbH
 |
 |  This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
 |  Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
 |  disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
 |  accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
 |  into with Oracle.
 |
 |  ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
 |  SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
 |  IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
 |  PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
 |  SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
 |  THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
 |
 |  Copyright &#169; 2015. All Rights reserved
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="asserter"
         xml:lang="en"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Identity Asserter Function with Oracle Access Manager</title>
  <para>
    This topic describes and illustrates the use of the Identity Asserter function with Oracle Access Manager WebGates.
    Processing is similar, with few exceptions, whether you have OAM 12c with 12c (or 11g, 10g) WebGates or OAM 10g with 10g WebGates).
    For instance, with Oracle Access Manager 12c, the Access Server is known as the OAM Server.
  </para>
  <para>
    All requests are first routed to a reverse proxy Web server and requests are
    intercepted by WebGate. The user is challenged for credentials based on the authentication scheme that is configured within Oracle Access Manager.
  </para>
  <para>
    The Identity Asserter function relies on perimeter authentication performed by WebGate on the Web Tier.
    Triggering the Identity Asserter function requires the appropriate chosen Active Type for your WebGate release.
  </para>
  <para>
    After triggering the Identity Asserter function, configured Authentication Providers (Login Modules) for constructing the Subject and populating it with the appropriate Principals are invoked.
  </para>
  <note>
    <para>
      The only difference between using the Identity Asserter function with 12c/11g WebGates versus 10g WebGates is the provider's chosen Active Type.
    </para>
  </note>
  <section xml:id="asserter-trigger">
    <title>Chosen Active Types</title>
    <para>
      The Identity Asserter function's Active Type configuration parameter lists supported values under the Available UI section.
      One of the following must be selected as the "Chosen" type to trigger the Identity Asserter function:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
      <listitem>
        <emphasis role="strong">Identity Assertion</emphasis>
        <para>
          Triggers Identity Assertion based on the trusted header <emphasis>OAM_IDENTITY_ASSERTION</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para><?linebreak?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <emphasis role="strong">Remote User</emphasis>
        <para>
          Triggers Identity Assertion based on <emphasis>OAM_REMOTE_USER</emphasis> header.
        </para>
        <para><?linebreak?></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <emphasis role="strong">ObSSOCookie</emphasis>
        <para>
          Triggers Identity Assertion based on <emphasis>ObSSOCookie</emphasis>.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      <emphasis>OAM_REMOTE_USER</emphasis> header includes the uid of the logged in user.
      Configuring <emphasis>OAM_REMOTE_USER</emphasis> as the chosen Active Type for the Identity Asserter requires Oracle Access Manager policies that set <emphasis>OAM_REMOTE_USER</emphasis> as part of the authorization success response headers.
    </para>
    <note>
      <para>
      </para>
    </note>
  </section>
</chapter>  