<!--
  ! This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
  ! Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
  ! disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
  ! accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
  ! into with Oracle.
  !
  ! ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
  ! SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
  ! IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
  ! PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
  ! SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
  ! THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
  !
  ! Copyright &#xA9; 2015. All Rights reserved
  !
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="principles-iam"
         xml:lang="en"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Principles</title>
  <section xml:id="principles-iam-01">
    <title>Understanding Deployment Projects</title>
    <para>
      Configurations and customizations in Oracle Identity and Access Management products can be migrated from one deployment to another deployment.
      For example, you might want to migrate the configurations and customizations from a test environment to a production environment. This is referred to as Test to Production (T2P).
    </para>
    <para>
      The Deployment Projects is tooling with exporting and importing Oracle Identity and Access Management configurations.
      Usually, you use the Deployment Project to migrate a configuration from one deployment to another, for example, from a test to a production deployment, or to create a backup of your system.
    </para>
    <para>
      You can save some or all of the objects in your configuration.
      This lets you develop and test your configurations in a test environment, and then import the tested objects into your production environment.
    </para>
    <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-01">
      <title>Features of the Deployment Project</title>
      <para>
        The Deployment Project helps you to migrate Oracle Identity and Access Management deployments from one server environment to another, such as from a testing environment to a staging environment or from a staging environment to a production environment.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-02">
      <title>Exporting Deployments</title>
      <para>
        You can export objects from your Oracle Identity and Access Management system and save them in an appropriate format.
        The Deployment Project leveraging scripts that lets you create your export file.
        Add objects by type, one type at a time, for example, roles, then forms, then processes, and so on.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-03">
      <title>Importing Deployments</title>
      <para>
        Objects that were exported into an appropriate format by using the export functionality can be imported into Oracle Identity and Access Management system by using the Deployment Project.
        You can import all or part of the files, and you can import multiple files at once.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-04">
      <title>Best Practices Related to Using the Deployment Manager</title>
      <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-04-01">
        <title>Do Not Export System Objects</title>
        <para>
          You should export or import system objects, for example, <emphasis role="strong">Request</emphasis>, <emphasis role="strong">Xellerate User</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="strong">System Administrator</emphasis> in Oracle Identity Manager, only when it is necessary.
          Exporting system objects from the testing and staging environments into production can cause problems.
          If possible, exclude system objects when exporting or importing data.
        </para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-04-02">
        <title>Exporting Related Groups of Objects</title>
        <para>
          Oracle recommends that you use the Deployment Projects to export sets of related objects.
          A unit of export should be a collection of logical items that you want to group together.
        </para>
        <para>
          Avoid exporting everything in the database in one operation, or exporting items one at a time.
          For example, suppose that you manage an integration between Oracle Identity Manager and a target system that includes processes, resource objects, adapters, IT resource type definitions, IT resource definitions, scheduled tasks, and so on.
          For this environment, you should create groups of related objects before exporting.
        </para>
        <para>
          For example, if you use the same e-mail definitions in multiple integrations, you should export the e-mail definitions as one unit, and the integrations as a different unit.
          This enables you to import changes to e-mail definitions independently of target system changes.
          On the other hand, if multiple resources use the same IT resource type definition, you can export and import the type definition separately from other data.
        </para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-04-03">
        <title>Exporting and Importing Data in Bulk</title>
        <para>
          The Deployment Projects are not tools for data movement or migration of large volumes of data.
          Use your judgement while using the Deployment Project to export/import objects.
          Entities, such as users, organizations, and roles, must be exported/imported by using other bulk tools, especially when the data volume is large.
        </para>
        <para>
          In addition, ensure that users, roles, and organizations are always loaded and/or synchronized before moving of configuration objects, such as policies, rules, application instances, and connector configuration, to avoid exporting/importing them as dependencies.
        </para>
      </section>
      <section xml:id="principles-iam-01-04-04">
        <title>Importing Data When the System Is Quiet</title>
        <para>
          You cannot complete an import operation in a single transaction because it includes schema changes.
          These changes affect currently running transactions on the system.
          To limit the effect of an import operation, temporarily disable the Web application for general use and perform the operation when the system has the least activity, for example, overnight.
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>