<!--
  ! This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
  ! Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
  ! disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
  ! accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
  ! into with Oracle.
  !
  ! ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
  ! SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
  ! IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
  ! PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
  ! SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
  ! THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
  !
  ! Copyright &#xA9; 2015. All Rights reserved
  !
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="workspace-iam"
         xml:lang="en"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Workspace Repository</title>
  <section xml:id="workspace-iam-01">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>
      The workspace use Global Consulting Delivery Portal (GCDP) for issue tracking and code sharing.
    </para>
    <section xml:id="workspace-iam-01-01">
      <title>What is Global Consulting Delivery Portal</title>
      <para>
        The code repository is CollabNet’s Enterprise Edition.
        This tool:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Is a hosted, web-based, collaborative project management and development environments a hosted, web-based, collaborative project management and development environment.
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Will allow project teams to gain greater control of their projects and processes via standardized and consistent delivery that supports our Project Management Standard Operating Procedures (PMSOPs) and Method.
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Provides a distributed development environment, and is available to all including our subcontractors and clients.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="workspace-iam-01-02">
      <title>Benefits to Projects and Members</title>
      <para>
        GCDP provides the Project Managers (PM's) and team members with a unified platform to collaborate and manage their work more effectively by enhancing:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Work Plan Management this allows the PM to upload Microsoft Project files and provides the team real time visibility to the project progress, milestones, and their own tasks
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Application Lifecycle Management a customizable Project Home page features quick access to Project artifacts and queries, Project Management and Implementation Method Materials, and Project Library upload and versioning
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Document and Code Management utilizing <emphasis role="strong">Subversion</emphasis> an open-source version control mechanism, allows multiple ways to manage documentation and code
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Project Tracking through the use of standardized risks, issues, problems, change requirements, and action workflow enabled templates
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Project Metrics which contains user customizable queries and reports with graphical representation of all artifact's attribute data residing within the OCDP tool
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Communication through the use of Project Announcements, Discussion Forums and Mailing Lists; all communication is archived Addition of an enhanced WIKI capability, new navigation and search functions
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        To make it easier for all participant of a project you should follow the guidelines for creation the workspace file structure.
      </para>
      <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Centralize the common Oracle Consulting artifacts
          </para>
          <para/>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Separate the customer project artifacts
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        This structure allows working on several customer projects where the code repositories are not always on the same server.
        The framework itself is expecting this workspace structure mentioned in File System Structure for its own purpose.
        Therefore, you will find in the version control systems the same hierarchy.
      </para>
      <para>
        This was required to make it possible to handle to different code repositories that the framework has seen during its lifetime.
        Each of the folders checked in a Subversion Repository.
        It is not possible to point in a folder hierarchy to different code repositories (or better it is not useful to spread a hierarchy across different Subversion Repositories).
      </para>
      <para>
        If you do so, it will not be possible to tag or branch the development artifacts.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="workspace-iam-02">
    <title>Checkout</title>
    <para>
      The code repository of Oracle Consulting Framework designed for the Oracle Identity and Access Management Product Family10g is still located in the Sample Code Repository of Oracle Technology Network.
      The code repository of Oracle Consulting Framework designed for the Oracle Identity and Access Management Product Family11g/12c product line goes to
      <link xl:show="new"
            xl:href="https://gcdp.oracle.com/"
            xl:role="http://docbook.org/xlink/role/olink">
        <citetitle>Global Consulting Delivery Portal</citetitle>
      </link>
    </para>
    <para>
      The Workspace provides the source and binaries and can checked out from the repositories mentioned above.
    </para>
    <para>
      To checkout the tree, perform the following steps:
    </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the Windows Explorer create a new directory <emphasis>D:\Project</emphasis> for example.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          From the Windows Explorernavigate to this directory.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          With a right-mouse-click, open the <emphasis role="strong">Context Menu</emphasis> for this folder.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Choose <emphasis role="strong">SVN Checkout...</emphasis> to open the Checkout Dialog.
        </para>
        <para/>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              As <emphasis role="strong">URL of repository</emphasis> type in:
            </para>
            <para/>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              As <emphasis role="strong">CheckOut Directory</emphasis> type in:
            </para>
            <para/>
            <para/>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="workspace-iam-03">
    <title>Structure</title>
    <para>
      To make it easier for all participant of the project you should follow the guidelines for creation of the Workspace Structure.
      The Workspace Structure consists of several directories:
    </para>
    <table frame="topbot" colsep="0" rowsep="1">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colname="c1" colwidth="2*"/>
        <colspec colname="c2" colwidth="3*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>Directory</entry>
            <entry>Purpose</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">FoundationFramework</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts shared across products</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">IdentityManager</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts related to Oracle Identity Governance</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">AccessManager</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts related to Oracle Access Manager</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">UnifiedDirectory</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts related to Unified Directory</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">InternetDirectory</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts related to Internet Directory</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry><emphasis role="strong">VirtualDirectory</emphasis></entry>
            <entry>the artifacts related to Virtual Directory</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>
</chapter>