<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
 |  Oracle Deutschland GmbH
 |
 |  This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
 |  Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
 |  disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
 |  accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
 |  into with Oracle.
 |
 |  ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
 |  SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
 |  IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
 |  PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
 |  SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
 |  THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
 |
 |  Copyright &#169; 2015. All Rights reserved
-->
<chapter xmlns   ="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xml:id  ="uid-about"
         version ="5.0">
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>
    For access to resources (applications, data) made available by the Police 20/20 program, the enhancement of the existing user IDs intended for this purpose with an additional P20/20 ID (hereinafter referred to as P20-UID) is described according to a uniform logic.
  </para>
  <para>
    This "Unique Identifier" (the P20-UID) is mapped in the Police Information Model (IMP).
    It is to be transmitted in the communication between the countries, the PSP / the Data Lake via the P20/20 interfaces.
    The P20-UID clearly identifies the responsible person for a query or a data change across all services.
    The P20-UID does not contain any personally identifiable data.
    An assignment to the person can only be made with the participation of the participant.
  </para>
  <para>
    The P20-UID is used for identification as well as for technical/data protection logging.
    Among other things, the country of origin, the (INPOL) participant or partner institutions that access P20/20 services should be directly derivable from it.
  </para>
  <para>
    This describes the generator's centrally provided administration and its exposed user interfaces.
  </para>
  <section xml:id  ="uid-about-term">
    <title>Terminology</title>
    <section>
      <title>Participant</title>
      <para>
        The police forces that take part directly in the Police 20/20 program are designated as participants, i.e. all state and federal police forces (BKA, Federal Police and Customs) in accordance with BKAG 29.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Partner</title>
      <para>
        Within this document, the authorities are considered to be partners who may access the services of the 20/20 program in the future as part of their sovereign tasks and/or police cooperation, but are not among the actual participants in Police 20/20.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Identity</title>
      <para>
        An identity is a clear, recognizable description of a natural person in a specific context of use.
        The identity consists of attributes that uniquely characterize the person.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>User Account</title>
      <para>
        A user account is authorized to access an IT system with restricted access.
        Therefore it would also be possible to assign a user account to a technical device (e.g. license plate reader, IoT device).
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="uid-about-ui">
    <title>Overview of the User Interface</title>
    <para>
      This chapter will help you familiarize with UID Administration User Interface.
      This will enable you to quickly find the information you need and complete the required tasks easily.
    </para>
    <para>
      The UID Administration User Interface provides features that serve most of the administrative task.
    </para>
    <para>
      The UID Administration User Interface is accessed either by logging directly into the application or by authenticating an upstream single sign-on procedure.
      After successful login, the home page is displayed as shown in Figure 2.1.
    </para>
    <figure xml:id="uid-about-home">
      <title>UID Administration Home Page</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <alt>UID Administration Home Page</alt>
        <imageobject>
          <!--
           | The location of the image path must be relative to xml:base set at
           | the enclosing book element
           -->
          <imagedata scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%" fileref="src/site/images/en/dashboard.png" format="PNG"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      The Home Page provides you a snapshot of the various features in UID Administration.
    </para>
    <section xml:id="uid-about-data">
      <title>Master Data Features</title>
    <para>
      The following master datafeatures are available:
    </para>
      <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='ptt-content'>Managing Participant Types</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='cnt-content'>Managing Countries</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='sta-content'>Managing States</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='pts-content'>Managing Participants</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='typ-content'>Managing Type</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="uid-about-security">
      <title>Security Features</title>
      <para>
        The following security features are available:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='tnt-content'>Managing Tenants</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='usr-content'>Managing Users</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link linkend='rol-content'>Managing Roles</link>
          <para/>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>