<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!--
  ! This software is the confidential and proprietary information of
  ! Oracle Corporation. ("Confidential Information").  You shall not
  ! disclose such Confidential Information and shall use it only in
  ! accordance with the terms of the license agreement you entered
  ! into with Oracle.
  !
  ! ORACLE MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THE
  ! SOFTWARE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE
  ! IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
  ! PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. ORACLE SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES
  ! SUFFERED BY LICENSEE AS A RESULT OF USING, MODIFYING OR DISTRIBUTING
  ! THIS SOFTWARE OR ITS DERIVATIVES.
  !
  ! Copyright (c) 2015. All Rights reserved
  !
-->
<legalnotice xml:id            ='legalnotice'
             xmlns             ='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook' version='5.0' xml:lang='en'
             xmlns:xlink       ='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'
             xmlns:xinclude    ='http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude'
             xmlns:xsi         ='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
             xsi:schemaLocation='http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd'>
  <?dbhtml filename='legalnotice.html'?>
  <mediaobject xml:id="figure-oracle-logo">
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-nd/3.0/88x31.png" format="PNG" align="center" />
    </imageobject>
    <caption>
      <para>This work is licensed under the <link xlink:href="https://www.oracle.com/technetwork/licenses/wls-dev-license-1703567.html">Oracle Technology Network Free Developer License Terms</link>.</para>
    </caption>
  </mediaobject>
  <para>To view a copy of this license, visit <link>https://www.oracle.com/technetwork/licenses/wls-dev-license-1703567.html</link> or send a letter to Oracle America, Inc., 500 Oracle Parkway, Redwood City, California 94065, USA.</para>
  <para>Trademarks are the property of their respective owners.</para>
  <para>
    UNLESS OTHERWISE MUTUALLY AGREED BY THE PARTIES IN WRITING, LICENSOR
    OFFERS THE WORK AS-IS AND MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND
    CONCERNING THE WORK, EXPRESS, IMPLIED, STATUTORY OR OTHERWISE,
    INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES OF TITLE, MERCHANTIBILITY, FITNESS
    FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, NONINFRINGEMENT, OR THE ABSENCE OF LATENT OR OTHER
    DEFECTS, ACCURACY, OR THE PRESENCE OF ABSENCE OF ERRORS, WHETHER OR NOT
    DISCOVERABLE. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF IMPLIED
    WARRANTIES, SO SUCH EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
  </para>
  <para>
    EXCEPT TO THE EXTENT REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW, IN NO EVENT WILL
    LICENSOR BE LIABLE TO YOU ON ANY LEGAL THEORY FOR ANY SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL,
    CONSEQUENTIAL, PUNITIVE OR EXEMPLARY DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS LICENSE OR
    THE USE OF THE WORK, EVEN IF LICENSOR HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF
    SUCH DAMAGES.
  </para>
</legalnotice>